EPISODE 23
Haode, it's not that I don't want to help.
It's just that this case
involves the Qiu, Wu, and Xu families.
It's really a tricky one.
It's not just the three families.
The Wu family's son
is engaged to a girl from the Lu family.
If the Lu family finds out,
they'll surely make a fuss.
Haode, these families
are either wealthy or noble.
We can't afford to get involved.
Mr. Du made judgments based on the law,
and Master Shen concurred with him.
Why go against him unnecessarily?
Kangning,
the Qiu family accuses the son
of the Wu family of adultery.
The Xu's accuse
the Qiu's and Wu's of adultery.
The Lu's will file a lawsuit
of deception in marriage.
The families are deadlocked.
You…
After all, you are married off
and no longer have the same heart as us.
They say the vows between men and women
violate marriage laws, and you just nod.
Afraid of her not being chaste enough,
they'd rather force Guiniang to die.
And you are the accomplices of murderers.
Leshan.
Who tipped off Madam Qiu
to catch the adulterers back then?
It couldn't be hidden for long.
It simply got exposed in advance.
Besides, we're trying
to find out a way for her.
Leshan,
this is not our fault.
Who is convicting Guiniang
of an adultery crime?
One of them
is the renowned third-ranked scholar,
and the other is Shen Huizhao,
the Heartless Judge.
We can't outdo them
in either wisdom or tactics.
As for me, I'll just admit defeat.
Go and tell Guiniang
to prepare the rope for hanging herself.
Stop.
What? You've changed your mind?
You've only been married for days,
and you've learned to play tricks.
That's right. She is so mischievous.
She resorts to reverse psychology
when scheming doesn't work.
Shouhua.
I'm begging you.
Please help Guiniang. I'm begging you.
Alright. I will help.
Who gave you the guarantee?
These last few days,
my eyes have also been…
Fuhui.
Second brother-in-law.
What were you doing?
Nothing. I was just looking.
Just looking.
Mr. Shen, please come inside.
Please.
Official Du, Judge Fang said he'd hold
a banquet at the Pan Restaurant for you.
- What act are you playing?
- Mr. Shen, you'll know once inside.
Mr. Shen, don't be anxious.
I've come to bring you news.
- What news?
- You are the last to marry into the Li…
Haode married you last.
You don't know about our secret alliance
of the sons-in-law.
So, they are all the Li family's
sons-in-law.
Except the eldest son-in-law, Du Yangxi,
the one who speaks out of turn
must be the eldest son of the Fan family
that Haode mentioned,
who is Fuhui's husband.
The other one
is naturally Master Chai,
owner of the Pan Restaurant.
Mr. Shen,
we've all heard about the case
of the Qiu family.
Now, Haode has asked
her elder sisters for help.
I wonder if you
have any good strategies to cope with it.
Cope with what?
You have no idea of the energy
of those women together.
They will stir chaos in the entire city.
Okay.
It's alright. No one's here.
Mr. Shen,
you'll understand as time passes.
The young ladies of the Li family
are very difficult to deal with.
They always try to gain the upper hand
over their husbands.
This time, they intend
to fight for Guiniang
and resist the verdict
of the Kaifeng Court.
This is no joking matter.
They are just some young ladies.
No need for such exaggeration.
It's just a minor case of moral conduct.
I don't know why you are all so concerned.
How the case is judged is not my concern.
But the news
has already reached your ears.
So, if I find myself in trouble,
you must help me as well.
That's the purpose
of the alliance of the sons-in-law.
- Right?
- Yes.
Mr. Shen,
I know that Qiu lady is your cousin.
Do you find it difficult?
If the Qiu lady and the son
of the Wu family are truly in love
and inseparable until death,
the desperate fighting
should've been done earlier.
She should persuade her parents to call
off the betrothal with the Xu's and Lu's
instead of pledging to marry Wu
in a sneaky way.
Now that she's been caught red-handed,
if I spare her,
wouldn't the laws of our country
become a joke?
Mr. Shen, in the court tomorrow,
those women will surely come to pester.
As for me, I can definitely hold steady.
I hope that you, Mr. Shen,
can hold steady too.
You must not let them coerce you.
This case shall be judged
according to the law.
No one can overturn it
or shake the marital laws of our country.
Mr. Shen,
you can't be so absolute in what you say.
I think we need to think more about it.
If they want to overturn this case,
where would they start?
Her father was so angry that he fell ill.
Had I known this,
I should have let them be together.
It's better than bringing it to the court.
Now, things are out of control.
Your hot temper
has caused so much trouble.
What's the use of regretting it now?
Never mind.
I'll set aside my pride
and go to their doors to mediate for you.
The Xu and Lu families
will definitely not agree.
Good day, Old Lady and Aunt.
Are you here to laugh at me again?
Stop that.
Haode, what's the matter?
Aunt, I'm here to relieve your worries.
Once you're at their homes,
you must absolutely endure.
Only then can you preserve the dignity
of Guiniang and your entire family.
Yes, Mother. I'll keep that in mind.
Old Lady. Aunt.
Where are you two going?
Huizhao, you are back.
The Qiu family has gotten into a lawsuit.
Old Lady is taking Aunt to the temple
to pray for blessings
and ask for a divination lot for Guiniang.
Will you join us?
Old Lady, you just recovered a bit
and shouldn't be overexerting yourself.
Aunt, if you want to go to the temple,
Haode can accompany you.
You simply want Guiniang to be caned.
Even your presence annoys me.
Move. Don't block the way.
Old Lady?
- Old Lady?
- Alas.
Aunt?
Li Haode.
What have you done again?
Guiniang cried so much her tears dried.
I must go comfort her.
I'm leaving, Huizhao.
Even with all your schemes exhausted,
you cannot defy the laws.
Just give up.
Alright, all who should be here
have arrived.
I've investigated
all the details.
Everyone, listen to the verdict.
A rightful marriage should be reached
with the consent of parents, the witness
of the matchmaker, and proper ceremonies.
Wu and Qiu pledge marriage secretly,
abandoning ritual propriety,
without shame, and not according
to marriage laws.
My Lord,
since ancient times,
there have been many more couples
who came together without those.
Pure quibbling.
Haode,
is this the great plan
you've come up with after an entire day?
I think Mr. Du overestimates you all.
What do you mean by "quibbling"?
Back then, Wenjun ran away with Xiangru.
"The melody of A Pair in Love"
has passed down till now.
Jiao Zhongqing and Liu Lanzhi died
against Jiao's mother's order,
and are celebrated through the ages.
After Zhu Yingtai went to study in Lin'an,
she shared a grave
with Liang Shanbo for eternity.
Prime Minister Xie An inscribed
on their tombstone,
saying Zhu Yingtai was righteous.
Without matchmakers or parental consent,
a couple can still be a tale for all time.
Can marriage laws restrain
the desires of human beings
and the myriad voices
of the people in the world?
The law must also comply
with human sentiments.
Yesterday, Old Lady personally went
to the Wu family
to mediate the marriage
between Guiniang and Wu Xiulin, right?
Although the combinations I spoke of
did not abide by marital laws,
they've become well-known for abiding
by natural laws and human feelings.
Moreover, regarding Mr. Wu and me,
our parents had agreed
to our marriage in the past.
Nonsense.
When did your families ever discuss
a marriage? How come I don't know?
My lord, our families have had
a marriage arrangement of them.
That's right.
Later on, we became enemies,
and the marriage was called off.
By faking a marriage agreement, they'll be
considered faithful to their prior pledge.
The secret affection
can be regarded as loyalty.
Thus, they can be exonerated
of the crime of adultery.
H-How do you know that?
That's a petty trick. Qingshi.
My lord is insightful.
They do want to exonerate themselves.
You claim that the marriage pledge
between you was set earlier
than the ones with the Xu's and Lu's.
Do you have evidence to prove it?
Though our parents changed their minds,
we have remained true to the pledge.
Aside from this paper
of marriage agreement,
we mutually pledged
to each other in marriage
through exchanged poetry
for three years. My lord,
I beg you to see the truth.
A POEM OF LOVE
Be it true or false.
Since the marriage was called off,
you should sever ties completely.
There is no reason
for undue private exchanges.
A few poems are not enough
to persuade Du Yangxi.
You're overestimating yourself.
Even if you're a good match
with a previously set marriage pledge,
you still shouldn't
peek through holes
and climb over walls to meet up, right?
Huizhao, so you're sure that I can't win?
Yes, I'm sure.
In the past, he could remain calm
even as the world crumbled before him.
He was reticent and restrained.
Now, he doesn't remember anything,
but he is better at irritating me.
To win the lawsuit,
we must see through my husband.
He does not love money nor seek profit.
What he loves is talent,
and what he seeks is fame.
Right now, he wants a good lawsuit
to make himself known throughout the land.
What kind of lawsuit
would become the talk of the town
and win him a reputation?
A lawsuit that involves talented people,
romantic love, and an unusual judgment.
If you grasp this point firmly,
you can influence him.
Even if you are insightful,
I have a counter tactic against that.
Did you write the poem?
Yes, my lord.
Guiniang and I have been engaged
since little. Our affection is deep.
Our families became enemies,
and we did not have the elders' blessing.
Yet my resolve is firm. If I can't
fulfill the pledge in this life,
I'd rather remain unmarried forever.
My lord, please see the truth.
A butterfly trapped in a cobweb,
unable to escape.
Can you write a poem for this?
Writing poetry in front of you
is like teaching a fish to swim.
Here is my poem. Due to its wild nature,
it has wandered the garden,
stealing the fragrance.
Now trapped by a cobweb,
it can only be set free
by the third-ranked scholar.
Great.
The last line is simply great.
Today, if I don't make
this beautiful romance come true,
it'll seem that I am too rigid
and lack compassion.
My lord, please hold firm.
I'd like to fulfill your wish,
but this matter also involves
the Xu and Lu families.
My lord, I have ruined the marriage pledge
between the Xu and Qiu families.
I'm truly sorry for that.
I wish to act as a matchmaker
for the Xu and Lu families
to make amends for my wrongdoing.
Good idea.
Our four families
should become sworn relatives.
From now on, we can interact as kin,
renew the friendships between us,
and forget all the grudges.
Isn't that wonderful?
- Well…
- My lord.
Lady Lu and Master Xu Wulang
are waiting outside for your summons.
Their timing is perfect. Let them in.
That's close.
Luckily, they are here in time.
That's a great idea, my lord.
We'll leave it to you to decide.
Wu and Qiu make one pair,
and Xu and Lu make another.
One mismatch by heaven has led
to the creation of two fine couples.
Since all of you intend to make peace,
I will grant your wishes.
Alright.
Later, when you are happily married,
don't forget me as the matchmaker.
My lord, you've made a wise judgment.
My lord, in the court…
I've heard it all.
Huizhao, did you foresee
the matchmaking in the court?
They are willingly withdrawing
the marriage pledges and lawsuit.
This can't be blamed on me, right?
I underestimated you.
My lady, this is the first time
I've seen someone
in this world who dares to oppose my lord.
You are truly audacious.
- Qingshi.
- I'm coming.
So stingy.
Huizhao,
are you really angry?
Huizhao?
You've helped us a lot.
I can't thank you enough.
It seems that you really like
this jade pendant.
Please take it.
Thank you, Lady Qiu.
Thank you, Haode.
Be good. Go ahead.
I've remembered your favor in my heart.
If you come to me seeking help,
I will see to it.
Aunt, I don't want your help on anything.
You may not today,
but you may in the future.
If the ladies
from the other branches bully you
or if Huizhao mistreats you,
I will help you.
Remember, those who treat you badly
are not necessarily evil,
and those who treat you well
are not necessarily good.
Alright, let's go.
I still have things to do.
Madam Qiu's way of expressing gratitude
is truly ingenious and uncommon.
You like it, right?
Haode, do you still remember
why you married into the Shen family?
I…
Do your utmost
to take down Shen Huizhao
and secure the position of his wife.
One can be lost to distractions.
You've buried your head
in the case files all day long.
Knowing your husband is upset,
yet you don't go and coax him.
You're straying too far
and too dull.
Worried about your marriage,
I've grown gray hair at such a young age.
Alright, I know, Mother Leshan.
I'll go coax him right now.
You…
My lord, it's time to take your medicine.
My lord?
Give it to me. You may leave.
Yes.
Huizhao,
if you don't open the door,
I'll go to Old Lady
and let her persuade you
to take your medicine.
Huizhao?
Huizhao, how come
you only caught the medicine and not me?
So, you are not mad at me anymore?
Who said I was mad at you?
Then why do you lock yourself
in the study all day long
without eating, drinking,
or taking your medicine?
Isn't it because you're blaming me
for handling Guiniang's case?
I'm not mad at you. I'm mad at myself.
When our ancestors made laws,
they spared no effort
on considering sentiment and reason.
If a law went against sentiment
or defied reason,
it couldn't be left
for future generations.
What does that mean?
I saw this note when I was browsing.
Although I can't remember at all,
the person who left this note for me
must be very important to me.
He means
that the ones who make the laws
must try their best to take into account
the sentiments and reason of the world.
Laws that contravene those
can't be passed down
to future generations.
Since those who create laws
are sentimental,
how can those who judge
be completely unsentimental?
Laws are supposed to be for the livelihood
and prosperity of the people.
As long as it complies
with the heavens or reason,
what should be supported
must be supported.
It's just that in the past,
I never truly comprehended this note.
This is quite strange.
You didn't understand it
when you were smart,
but now you do when you
become silly after taking a fall.
It's because of you.
Me?
Am I that important?
Thank you for what you did for Guiniang.
- I--
- My lady, Old Lady wants to see you.
- Actually, I--
- Go ahead.
Old Lady, please don't blame me
for being talkative.
Huizhao is the sole heir
of the eldest branch.
He'll inherit the Shen family
in the future.
His wife, however, comes
from a family with no foundation.
She has dull talent and coarse behavior.
She doesn't know how to serve elders
or the etiquette of noble families.
Not to mention the other families
she will socialize with in the future,
even the other branches of the Shen family
laugh at her behind her back.
Then what do you suggest?
To say something improper,
one inevitably seeks any treatment
in desperation.
Luckily, their marriage
has not been widely publicized,
and few in the capital are aware of it.
When they truly consummate
their marriage one day,
it will mean that Huizhao's heart knot
has been untied
and he can totally
marry another noble lady.
As for Li Haode,
with her background and insight,
she can absolutely not be his wife.
Old Lady, Lady Haode is here.
Let her in.
Haode,
what secret are you hiding
that you haven't told me?
Does Old Lady mean Leshan?
Alright, stop hiding it from me.
You go to Huizhao's study every night.
What do you go there for?
Old Lady, Huizhao hasn't fully recovered
and often feels tired.
But he can't rest easy about work duties,
so he forces himself to attend to them.
But the files are numerous
and seemingly never-ending.
As his wife,
when there is a possibility to help,
how dare I shirk it onto others?
I simply read files
for Huizhao in the study.
I dare not interfere
with official matters.
You are his wife, not his page.
I told you to go to the study room,
not to let you read files for him.
Haode,
do you know why I didn't help you
when those three branches
caused you trouble?
You want to test my composure and conduct.
Haode,
you cannot always avoid.
You must quickly learn
to manage household affairs
and take on the heavy responsibility
of the lady of the house.
Only then will you not let down
my high expectations of you.
Qingshi.
- My lord.
- Hasn't my wife come back yet?
Well… How about I go
and find out some news?
My lord. My lord.
It's so late. Where are you going?
My lord?
Old Lady and Young Master Huizhao
are very frugal in their daily lives.
There don't seem to be many servants
in the mansion.
But considering those nannies, maids,
and servants
from the estates outside,
the number is no less than 200.
The daily expenses
and the reciprocal social exchanges
all need to be recorded item by item
in the account books.
Your ability to tally
and check the accounts
is absolutely indispensable.
Who is outside?
Grandmother, it's me.
I heard that after dusk,
you summoned the housekeeper
and asked for the ledgers
of the past half year.
I feared that you'd stay up all night
checking accounts again,
so I came to take a look.
Are you worried that I can't endure it,
or that she can't?
Grandmother,
these matters can't be rushed.
We can take our time.
Even if I'm healthy now,
I cannot live to be a hundred.
When the day comes that I die,
who will manage
the household affairs for you?
Who will manage our fields and estates?
And who will socialize
with our family's friends?
The Shen family
can't be without a capable lady
to manage the household.
Huizhao,
I'm truly worried about you.
Grandmother,
I've always been independent
in the imperial court,
never seeking to associate
with the powerful officials.
So, my wife naturally
doesn't need to humble herself
to socialize
with the noble families' ladies.
As for the account books,
we can give them
to the trustworthy old housekeeper
to spare us the trouble
over trivial matters.
I've troubled your wife enough.
Take her away.
She's young and naive by nature.
To familiarize her with household affairs,
it will cost a lot of effort from you.
I'm just worried about you.
Alright, I know.
Just go.
What are you waiting for?
Old Lady, I'll take my leave.
We're leaving.
You may leave. I'll do it myself.
Let's go back.
My lord, Lord Xue
from the Dali Supreme Court has arrived.
Let him in quickly.
Please.
That will do. Be extremely careful.
I was not aware of your visit.
Sorry for not welcoming you in advance.
Mr. Shen, no need for such courtesy.
It is I who have come uninvited
and disturbed you.
Greetings, Mr. Shen. I'm Geng Kaixing.
Lord Xue, please.
Last month, our office
had several criminal affairs
that were jointly adjudicated
with Kaifeng Court.
Due to their significant importance,
I can't fully trust the subordinates,
so I'm here to discuss the matter
of reporting to His Majesty with you.
Official Xue,
don't you have case files
to transfer to Judge Fang?
Go ahead.
Yes.
I wonder which case is so important
to warrant your personal visit.
Is the wound on your head fully healed?
I appreciate your concern.
It's just a superficial wound.
After some rest,
it's no longer a serious issue.
A superficial wound? Back when you
first got involved in criminal justice,
I tested your knowledge.
You answered everything fluently
concerning the laws of recent years,
far surpassing the officials of our office
and the Ministry of Punishments.
As a young man of quick understanding
with an exceptional memory,
why do you resort to this
when you handle cases now?
CATEGORIES OF LAWS
Lord Xue…
You're so confused you can't recognize me,
yet you say it's a superficial wound.
When you served as the magistrate
of Fengqiu County,
you offended the local powerful houses.
Who pleaded for you in the imperial court?
When you entered Kaifeng Court
to become an official,
who was it that recommended you?
And who is the author
of the inscription in this book?
Jingwei, when we meet in private,
we've always addressed each other
as master and student.
After Geng Kaixing left,
the words you spoke
gave you away immediately.
Master?
You've finally remembered.
- But why would you--
- Why would I suspect you?
You've always supported
using harsh laws to remedy societal ills.
When judging cases,
you only delivered heavy sentences.
But in this past month,
the cases you handled
were sentenced leniently and with mercy.
You thought you had concealed it
tightly without a leak.
But to the observant,
there were flaws everywhere.
How about it?
Having this book with you,
have you gained any insights?
Only now do I understand,
the note you wrote me
was meant to teach me
to discern the ways of the world
and human sentiments when handling cases.
After teaching you for so many years,
I couldn't get through to your blockhead.
I wonder who it was
that changed you,
my disciple with a heart of stone.
ZHENG SU'E
- Let go!
- You condemned prisoner.
- Resisting, aren't you?
- Let go!
How dare you harass a noble lady?
- Drag her away.
- Let go! Let go now!
Let go!
Let go, you condemned prisoner.
- Do you want to die now?
- Haode!
Let go!
- Let go!
- Let go now!
Come here.
Hold her down.
Don't move.
S-S-She has no tongue.
What has happened?
Well, she is a condemned prisoner
being escorted to the capital.
Having just undergone a court session,
she has gone mad suddenly.
My apologies for startling you.
I'm actually accustomed to this.
I'm afraid it may have scared the ladies.
- Drag her away quickly.
- Yes.
Move!
Jingwei, hurry
and take your wife back home.
My lady, the bathing water
of the Buddha has been spilled.
Let's hurry back.
- Haode.
- Haode?
Huizhao.
Mr. Du, I have a message
from Shouhua for you.
May I have a word in private?
This way, please.
She doesn't have a tongue.
So, she is the one…
- That's scary.
- …who changed your heart, isn't she?
Mountains don't change when it rains.
How could your disciple waver so easily?
Alright.
Let's get back to business.
There is indeed an important case
that I need to discuss with you.
About the Imperial Censorate.
Let's discuss inside.
SHEN'S MANSION
I don't want tea.
Nor do I want medicine. I'm already well.
I made these candied treats personally.
A secret recipe passed down
through generations of Li's.
I used top-quality glutinous rice
to steam honey cakes.
I know you don't like mixed fruits,
so I used apricots instead.
And there are
fragrant dumplings too. Look.
I didn't make them myself.
I bought them from the best confectioner
on Dashitou Alley.
I went there myself. Have a taste.
Speak up. What do you want again?
- The condemned prisoner today…
- Stop.
You can't eat these unless you agree.
Huizhao, just help me out.
Now, whenever I close my eyes,
I see her face.
The cruel official
had her tongue pulled out,
and she can't read.
During today's court session,
she couldn't even say her grievances.
She's truly too pitiable.
The official who cut her tongue
is imprisoned awaiting punishment.
I know.
I heard that her mother-in-law
and her child
have been waiting outside the prison
just to see her once.
Please grant her some mercy.
That child is only four
or five years old now.
If you sentence her mother to death,
it might be the last time
they see each other.
This won't violate any laws, right?
Huizhao, I'm begging you.
Killing one's husband is a grave sin,
among the ten abominations.
- So, my answer is no.
- My lord.
I've brought the new case files.
What are you doing?
If you don't agree, I won't come down.
- My lord?
- If you don't agree, I won't come down.
- I'm coming in now.
- Hurry down now!
- Get out now!
- Yes.
- Leave the files behind.
Alright, get up.
She is about to be executed soon.
Yet you won't even let her
see her family for the last time.
Someone as cold-hearted as you
is not deserving of eating sweet treats.
- I'll eat these myself.
- Half an hour.
What?
Tomorrow, Official Du and I
will inspect the death row cells.
You bring them over.
But you'll only have half an hour.
Enough. Half an hour is enough.
I knew you were the best.
I'll go get you some sweet treats.
Even the weather in June
doesn't change as fast as your face.
KAIFENG COURT'S PRISON
Su'e.
Silly girl, she is your mother.
She is your mother. Hurry.
Su'e.
Her daughter-in-law killed her son.
She doesn't resent her,
but instead has come to see her.
That's really strange.
Call her mother.
During the previous two court sessions,
Zheng did not utter a word in court.
So, the original sentence
was upheld in the end.
Now, the case
has been transferred to Kaifeng.
This is her last chance to survive.
I have interrogated Yang Zigao,
magistrate of Xianping County.
According to him,
once a death row inmate
ultimately gets acquitted,
the original judging officials
will be sentenced to the same punishment.
For that, he cut her tongue.
He even ranted, saying that
it's the usual practice of low officials.
Cruel officials are not rare
in many places.
They would cut out tongues
or poison prisoners to mute them,
making it impossible to seek justice
before the execution,
to avoid repeated inquiries and reports.
She cried for injustice repeatedly,
must have a reason.
But she didn't speak up in the court.
Maybe the person who framed her
is of no ordinary status.
I agree.
But now that she's mute and illiterate,
how can she state her grievances?
My lord, as the poor,
we're struggling to make a living.
With my son gone,
if I lose my daughter-in-law again,
how am I and my granddaughter
supposed to survive?
My lord, please have mercy.
- Please have mercy, my lord.
- Get up.
Granny Zhang, murdering one's husband
is punishable by hanging.
How was the relationship between your son
and his wife in the past?
For what reason
did she murder her husband?
My daughter-in-law has been
in our family for seven years.
The two of them have never had a quarrel
or exchanged a cross word.
A year ago, on the eighth day
of the fourth month,
I returned from offering incense
to find my son had been killed.
Mother.
Later, the officials
arrested my daughter-in-law
and sentenced her to death.
I'm just an old woman.
I have no way to seek justice
for my grievances.
The Zhang family of four
was originally supported by Zhang Min
by cutting wood, making charcoal,
and doing odd jobs.
Later, while he was repairing the roof,
he accidentally fell and broke his leg.
He could only recuperate at home.
To support the family, Zheng Su'e
came to the capital to become a nanny.
A year ago, on the night
of the third day of the fourth month,
Zheng Su'e suddenly returned home
at midnight and refused to go out.
On the eighth day, her husband Zhang Min
was killed with a firewood cleaver.
After the neighbors reported it,
the officials immediately arrested Zheng.
She spoke incoherently in court,
claiming that she killed her own husband,
and was ultimately sentenced to death.
After Zheng Su'e came to the capital,
at whose house did she work as a nanny?
According to the broker Xu Er, she was
first hired by the Tians in Jingfufang.
Within a month, she went to work
for the Liu family in Guozi Alley,
mainly doing mending and cleaning.
Xu Er doesn't know
what happened after that.
I've interrogated both families.
Nothing was amiss.
My family once hired such people as well.
Most of the contracts signed
are short-term.
At most half a year,
or as little as one month.
A contract doesn't even need to be signed.
When we're too busy, we'll hire help
for cooking, sewing, and cleaning.
It only costs about
a hundred or so coins per day.
That's true.
Mr. Shen,
do you think the reason
for Zheng Su'e returning home
late at night is related to the case?
She was hired by the Tian family.
Why did she suddenly disappear
in less than a month?
The Tian family's matriarch is jealous
and cannot tolerate other women.
Zheng Su'e is good-looking,
unlike a coarse peasant woman.
It may be the root cause of trouble.
Huizhao, your words
are quite unreasonable.
Wealth and beauty have been
deadly temptations since ancient times.
But those who covet wealth and beauty
are not women.
Why blame her without reason?
I had hoped
that you could be fair and just.
Instead, you've started to blame her.
That's not fair at all.
Let's go.
You are speaking up for Zheng.
Then, can you get her to speak?
I…
Subtitle translation by: Grace Zhao